# 首先我们准备小米辣200克
First, prepare 200g of "Xiaomila" chili peppers
# 将小米辣清洗干净之后切碎备用
Rinse and mince the peppers and set them aside
# 辣椒切得越碎则越辣和入味
The thinner you slice them, the more spicy and rich it is
# 准备二荆条500克去掉辣椒蒂之后切碎备用
Prepare 500g of "Erjingtiao" chili peppers, remove the stems and mince them
# 不能吃太辣的同学可以用大青椒或者大红椒代替
If you don't want it to be too spicy, you can replace with green or red bell peppers
# 准备杏鲍菇1根切成小粒备用
Prepare a king oyster mushroom and dice it
# 杏鲍菇的重量是350克
The king oyster mushroom should weigh about 350g
# 加杏鲍菇的目的是代替味精增加鲜味
Adding the king oyster mushroom would enhance the umami taste without having to add MSG
# 同学们也可以改变比例多加一些杏鲍菇
You can also adjust the ratio and add more king oyster mushroom
# 这样还能丰富辣椒酱的口感
This also enriches the texture of the chili paste
# 杏鲍菇切好之后下一步开始准备辅料
After cutting the king oyster mushroom, we start to prepare other minor ingredient
# 准备生姜和大蒜各100克剁碎备用
Prepare 100g of ginger and 100g of garlic and mince them
# 生姜和大蒜可以适量的多加一些
You can add some more if you want
# 这样能够让香味更加浓郁
This makes the taste rich and dense
# 准备空碗一个
Prepare an empty bowl
# 加入炒香的白芝麻20克
Add 20g of roasted sesame
# 没有芝麻的同学也可以不加
You can also ignore this step if you don't have sesame
# 加入刀口辣椒面30克
Add 30g of Daokou chili powder
# 加辣椒面的目的是增加成品的层次感
Adding chili powder gives our final product another layering of taste
# 下一步开始准备香料
Next, prepare the spices
# 碗中加入八角2颗
Add two star anises to the bowl
# 加入桂皮2小块
Add two pieces of cinnamon
# 加入香叶2片
Add two pieces of bay leaves
# 加入几根小葱挽成结
Add a few scallions and tie a knot
# 再加入几根香菜
Then add a few corianders
# 然后在剁好的辣椒中加入食用盐15克搅拌均匀
Then add 15g of salt to the chili paste and mix everything
# 这一步的目的是让辣椒提前出水和入味
This step is to marinate the chili peppers and remove the moisture
# 下一步开始制作
Next, start making the paste
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First, we heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入菜籽油700克 烧至6成热（约180度）
After the wok is heated, add 700g of canola oil and heat to 60% (around 180 degrees)
# 油温6成热之后将准备好的香料和小葱香菜下锅
When the oil is heated, add the prepared spices, scallion, and coriander
# 然后转中小火浸炸3分钟左右
Then down the heat to medium/small and fry for around 3 minutes
# 这一步的目的是将香料和辅料炸出香味
This is to fry the spices and minor ingredients till the good flavor comes out
# 家庭小灶则需要5分钟左右
If you cook at home, it takes around 5 minutes
# 3分钟之后将辅料捞出丢弃不用
3 minutes later, take these ingredients out and throw them away
# 然后再次将油温升至7成热
Then heat the oil to 70% again
# 油温7成热之后将切好的杏鲍菇下锅炸3分钟
After the oil is 70% heated, add the sliced king oyster mushroom to fry for 3 minutes
# 这一步的目的是减少杏鲍菇的水份
This is to remove the moisture from the king oyster mushroom
# 中途加入剁好的姜蒜末炸香
Add the minced ginger and garlic midway to fry
# 杏鲍菇炸至金黄色之后（3分钟）再加入切好的辣椒
After the king oyster mushroom turns yellow (3 minutes), add the chili paste
# 辣椒碎下锅之后先开大火烧开搅拌均匀
After the chili paste is added to the wok, turn to high heat, boil it, and mix everything
# 拌匀之后开中火熬4分钟
After mixing, turn to medium heat for 4 minutes
# 这一步的目的是将其熬至断生
This is to soften the ingredients
# 同学们只有熬至断生之后可以防止变质
Only when everything is soften can the chili paste be prevented from going bad
# 4分钟之后加入准备好的刀口辣椒和熟芝麻
4 minutes later, add the prepared chili powder and roasted sesame
# 然后继续翻炒2分钟
Then continue to stir-fry for 2 minutes
# 刀口辣椒炒香炒出颜色之后再加入黄豆酱50克
When the chili powder turns to a bright color, add 50g of bean paste
# 黄豆酱翻炒1分钟之后即可出锅冷却食用
Stir-fry the bean paste for a minute and the paste will be ready when it cools down
# 同学们辣椒酱冷却之后最好放入玻璃瓶中密封保存
When it cools down, it's the best to store it in a glass jar
# 一道鲜辣回味无穷的辣椒酱就制作完成
We've finished making a tasty and spicy spice paste
# 下面开始技术总结
Now, we'll summarize the key techniques
# 第一，不同地区的同学可以选择适合自己辣度的辣椒
First, you can choose what kind of chili pepper to use depending on your location and how spicy you want it to be
# 第二，最好选择菜籽油作为油料，且油量可以稍微多一些，这样可以增加保存的时间
Secondly, the canola oil is the best and adding more oil can let you store it for longer
# 第三，此酱除了下饭之外还可以用作蒸鱼头的原料
Thirdly, this paste can not only go along with rice but also be used to steam fish heads
# 第四，冷却之后最好用密封容器放入冰箱保存
Fourthly, when it cools down, it's the best to seal the jar and store it in the fridge
# 第五，成品切忌阳光暴晒或者阴暗潮湿
Fifthly, don't expose the paste in sunlight or store it in moisturous environment
# 家常辣椒酱的技术总结完毕
Above is all the tips for making chili paste